<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2003 on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/2003/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2003 on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/2003/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Evolution: From Promise to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-march-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-march-2003/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth Matures By March 2003, Bluetooth had matured significantly. What was experimental in 2002 was becoming production-ready. We weren&amp;rsquo;t just prototyping anymore; we were building devices that would ship to millions of users.&#xA;Optimizing for Production I spent weeks optimizing Bluetooth solutions for real-world deployment. We were now thinking about data floods—not just from users, but from the Bluetooth ecosystem itself. Multiple devices connecting, interfering with each other, creating cascade effects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symbian OS: The Mobile Operating System Wars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/symbian-os-hacks-motorola/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/symbian-os-hacks-motorola/</guid>
      <description>The OS Wars Intensify By January 2003, it was clear that mobile phones were becoming mini-computers. The question was: what operating system would power them? Windows Mobile existed but was bloated. Linux was open source but immature on mobile. And there was Symbian—an elegant operating system designed specifically for mobile devices from the ground up.&#xA;Motorola was exploring Symbian. At the factory floor, I spent weeks scaling Symbian solutions—trying to understand how to build robust, feature-rich applications on this novel platform.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
