<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OCI on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/oci/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OCI on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 22:43:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/oci/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From First Principles to Zettascale: How OCI&#39;s GPU/RDMA Architecture Redefines AI Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/summary-gpu-oci-first-principles-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 22:43:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/summary-gpu-oci-first-principles-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; This article reflects my personal research and analysis based on publicly available information and is not representative of my employer&amp;rsquo;s official position.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI infrastructure, one company has quietly revolutionized how we think about GPU computing at scale. Through a series of &amp;ldquo;First Principles&amp;rdquo; engineering blogs and groundbreaking deployments, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) has demonstrated that starting from fundamental physics and systems design—rather than following industry conventions—can yield extraordinary results. This is the story of how OCI went from concept to operating the world&amp;rsquo;s largest GPU superclusters, and what it means for the future of AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Weeks in Batam: Bringing NVIDIA GB200 to Life on the Data Plane</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three weeks in Batam, Indonesia in March 2025. Not a vacation - something far more meaningful. I was there to help bring the NVIDIA GB200 data plane to life, working alongside some of the brightest minds at OCI and NVIDIA. This was the moment where cutting-edge technology meets real-world infrastructure, and I got to be part of making it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Related readings:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/cloud-infrastructure/post/behind-the-scenes-nvidia-gb200-nvl72-oci-apis&#34;&gt;Behind the Scenes: NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 on OCI APIs&lt;/a&gt; - Technical deep dive on the NVIDIA GB200 and OCI integration&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.oracle.com/cloud-infrastructure/post/supercluster-nvidia-blackwell-dedicated-alloy&#34;&gt;Supercluster: NVIDIA Blackwell Dedicated Alloy&lt;/a&gt; - OCI&amp;rsquo;s Supercluster offering with Blackwell GPUs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacenterdynamics.com/en/news/nvidia-gb200-nvl72-now-available-via-oracle-cloud/&#34;&gt;Nvidia GB200 NVL72 Now Available via Oracle Cloud&lt;/a&gt; - Data Center Dynamics coverage of the launch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-mission-time-to-market&#34;&gt;The Mission: Time to Market&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I arrived in Batam, the pressure was real. GB200 was new. NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s latest breakthrough in GPU technology. OCI was committed to being first to market with it. And the data plane - the critical infrastructure layer that handles every packet, every connection, every byte moving through these machines - needed to be battle-ready.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
