<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 22:43:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From First Principles to Zettascale: How OCI&#39;s GPU/RDMA Architecture Redefines AI Infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/summary-gpu-oci-first-principles-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 22:43:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/summary-gpu-oci-first-principles-blog/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: This article reflects my personal research and analysis based on publicly available information and is not representative of my employer&amp;rsquo;s official position.&#xA;In the rapidly evolving landscape of AI infrastructure, one company has quietly revolutionized how we think about GPU computing at scale. Through a series of &amp;ldquo;First Principles&amp;rdquo; engineering blogs and groundbreaking deployments, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) has demonstrated that starting from fundamental physics and systems design—rather than following industry conventions—can yield extraordinary results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oracle AI World 2025: Enterprise AI from Promise to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</guid>
      <description>The AI Inflection Point At Oracle AI World 2025, a clear message emerged: AI isn&amp;rsquo;t just another technology trend—it&amp;rsquo;s the bridge between decades of enterprise data and the future of business innovation.1&#xA;Unlocking Enterprise Data&amp;rsquo;s True Potential Oracle founder Larry Ellison framed the opportunity succinctly: &amp;ldquo;AI offers the highest-value technology we have ever seen so far.&amp;rdquo;2 The critical insight? Most AI models train on internet data, missing the real competitive advantage: enterprise databases containing mission-critical business information.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
