<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welcome to Rik Kisnah&#39;s Blog on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welcome to Rik Kisnah&#39;s Blog on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oracle AI World 2025: Enterprise AI from Promise to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</guid>
      <description>The AI Inflection Point At Oracle AI World 2025, a clear message emerged: AI isn&amp;rsquo;t just another technology trend—it&amp;rsquo;s the bridge between decades of enterprise data and the future of business innovation.1&#xA;Unlocking Enterprise Data&amp;rsquo;s True Potential Oracle founder Larry Ellison framed the opportunity succinctly: &amp;ldquo;AI offers the highest-value technology we have ever seen so far.&amp;rdquo;2 The critical insight? Most AI models train on internet data, missing the real competitive advantage: enterprise databases containing mission-critical business information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mauritius Summer Holidays 2025 - Three Weeks of Family, Legacy, and New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mauritius-summer-holidays-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mauritius-summer-holidays-2025/</guid>
      <description>I spent three unforgettable weeks in Mauritius during July-August 2025. This trip was special in so many ways - it was about honoring family legacy, building new opportunities, and celebrating the people who matter most.&#xA;1. Baptism of Laxmi Villa - A Dream Reborn Estelle and I completed the renovation of Laxmi Villa, the house Dad and Ma built in 1999 after I left Mauritius. The three-floor structure has always held meaning for our family:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Weeks in Batam: Bringing NVIDIA GB200 to Life on the Data Plane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks in Batam, Indonesia in March 2025. Not a vacation - something far more meaningful. I was there to help bring the NVIDIA GB200 data plane to life, working alongside some of the brightest minds at OCI and NVIDIA. This was the moment where cutting-edge technology meets real-world infrastructure, and I got to be part of making it happen.&#xA;Related readings:&#xA;Behind the Scenes: NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 on OCI APIs - Technical deep dive on the NVIDIA GB200 and OCI integration Supercluster: NVIDIA Blackwell Dedicated Alloy - OCI&amp;rsquo;s Supercluster offering with Blackwell GPUs Nvidia GB200 NVL72 Now Available via Oracle Cloud - Data Center Dynamics coverage of the launch The Mission: Time to Market When I arrived in Batam, the pressure was real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too Young to Die</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-young-to-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-young-to-die/</guid>
      <description>A poem for my brother. Reflecting on life, family, and the passage of time. In Remembrance Memorial and Remembrance for Ranjiv&#xA;Too Young to Die Once I was four years old, i told my mama &amp;ldquo;Pretty woman walking down the streah haha&amp;rdquo; Then she shouted at me and i said mama &amp;ldquo;You ugly woman, yacking down the stream yah&amp;rdquo;&#xA;That was then and the world was smaller And everything was so simpler and life was gentler My brother and I were running down the roads in Sodnac Drinking our dad&amp;rsquo;s secret stash of cognac</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iPod Integration Journey: From Dream to Modular Architecture (2002-2003)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ipod-integration-journey-2002-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ipod-integration-journey-2002-2003/</guid>
      <description>The iPod Phenomenon and the Integration Dream In May 2002, Apple&amp;rsquo;s iPod was just a year old but already reshaping how people thought about digital music. At Motorola, we faced a critical question: how do we integrate iPod functionality into mobile devices?&#xA;The vision was seductive: your phone would be your music player. Not two devices—one elegant handset that played music, made calls, managed contacts, and did everything in between. What followed was over a year of iterative development that fundamentally shaped my understanding of modular systems and scalable architecture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Prototypes: From Experimental to Production (2002-2003)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-journey-2002-2003/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-journey-2002-2003/</guid>
      <description>The Bluetooth Promise (August 2002) By August 2002, Bluetooth had been standardized for a few years, but actual working implementations were still rare. The promise was revolutionary: wirelessly connect your phone to headsets, computers, other devices—all without wires, all at close range.&#xA;At Motorola, we saw Bluetooth as the future. Instead of wired connections or limited infrared, devices could communicate wirelessly over a distance of 10 meters. You could leave your headset at your desk and walk around the office with your phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3G Rollout: The Future of Mobile Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/3g-rollout-thrills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/3g-rollout-thrills/</guid>
      <description>Moving to Motorola In 2002, I left academia and joined Motorola Mobile Devices. The timing was perfect. Motorola was at the center of the 3G revolution—the transition from 2G networks (which enabled SMS and basic data) to 3G networks (which promised high-speed data and multimedia).&#xA;The 3G Vision The promise was intoxicating. Imagine a mobile phone that could stream video, enable real-time applications, support navigation and location services. 3G would deliver megabits per second instead of kilobits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Y2K Debugging Journey: From Crisis to Lessons Learned (1999-2001)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k-debugging-journey-1999-2001/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/y2k-debugging-journey-1999-2001/</guid>
      <description>The Millennium Bug Looms As an NTU student in Singapore during the waning days of 1998 and early 1999, I found myself swept up in what would become the defining technical challenge of the era: Y2K debugging. The humid labs of Nanyang Technological University buzzed with anxiety and excitement as midnight on December 31st approached—would systems across the world crash when the calendar rolled from 1999 to 2000?&#xA;In 1999, Y2K debugging was all the rage in my corner of the tech world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Linux at NTU: Open Source Becomes Real</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/early-linux-at-ntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/early-linux-at-ntu/</guid>
      <description>The Linux Revolution Reaches NTU By September 2001, Linux was transitioning from hobbyist project to legitimate alternative to proprietary Unix systems. NTU, as a forward-thinking institution, started deploying Linux in labs. After years of expensive proprietary systems, here was an free, open operating system that actually worked.&#xA;For students raised on Windows, encountering Linux was revelatory. The source code was available. You could modify it. You could understand how everything worked down to the kernel level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Applets Journey: Write Once, Run Anywhere? (2000)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/java-applets-journey-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/java-applets-journey-2000/</guid>
      <description>Java: The Future of Computing (February 2000) In February 2000, just two months after the Y2K celebration, the tech world buzzed with a different promise: write once, run anywhere. Java was going to revolutionize computing. Sun Microsystems was betting big on applets—small Java programs that would run in web browsers, turning the browser into a universal application platform.&#xA;As an NTU student in the dorms, I had front-row access to this revolution.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wi-Fi Experiments: From Lab to Campus Networks (1999-2000)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-experiments-journey-1999-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-experiments-journey-1999-2000/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Revolution Begins (July 1999) By July 1999, Wi-Fi technology was emerging from IEEE 802.11 specifications into practical reality. Singapore, as a forward-thinking tech hub, was one of the first places to experiment with widespread wireless networking. As an NTU student, I had access to some of these early deployments, and the possibilities seemed limitless.&#xA;I spent weeks debugging solutions for wireless connectivity. The early Wi-Fi standards had significant challenges. Signal attenuation was unpredictable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matrix Neural Net Dreams: Reflections from 1999</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/matrix-neural-net-dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/matrix-neural-net-dreams/</guid>
      <description>The Dream of Artificial Intelligence In May 1999, while the world was preoccupied with the approaching Y2K crisis, I found myself exploring something entirely different in the NTU labs: neural networks. The term &amp;ldquo;neural net dreams&amp;rdquo; might sound whimsical now, but in 1999, this was genuinely visionary work. We were exploring how computers could learn from data, much like the human brain.&#xA;The Technical Challenge Matrix operations are the backbone of neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Welcome to my corner of the internet. I&amp;rsquo;m a technology enthusiast and professional based in the tech industry, passionate about exploring innovative solutions and sharing knowledge.&#xA;Professional Background I focus on technology, infrastructure, and creative problem-solving. My experience spans multiple domains, and I&amp;rsquo;m continuously learning and adapting to new technologies and methodologies.&#xA;What This Blog Is About On this blog, I share insights about technology, best practices, and interesting topics I encounter in my professional journey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications &amp;amp; Articles A collection of my written work and articles on technology, society, and civil discourse.&#xA;Featured Publications Behind the Scenes: NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 on OCI APIs&#xA;Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Blog Technical deep-dive into NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s latest GPU architecture integration with OCI Focus on HPC/GPU infrastructure and performance optimization Race Counts Against New Citizen When Renting House&#xA;Straits Times Forum &amp;amp; Think Centre Singapore August 23, 2006 Personal account of racial discrimination in Singapore&amp;rsquo;s housing market More publications coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/resume/</guid>
      <description>Rik Kisnah Senior Principal Engineer (HPC/GPU) at Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) for AI/ML Infrastructure Seattle, Washington, United States&#xA;&amp;ldquo;In God we Trust, all others bring data&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Summary Experienced Engineer with domain expertise in DevOps/CICD/Testing/Automation/HPC/GPU/ML/AI in the Cloud. My passion is building teams and solving big-scale problems.&#xA;Products delivered chronologically: Motorola phones, Aeroflex PXI, Amazon Kindle, AWS EC2 Windows, AWS Workspaces, AWS Load Balancers, Oracle Cloud Bare Metal, Oracle HPC/GPU.&#xA;Contact Information Location: Seattle, Washington Phone: +1 206 724 5771 Email: rikesh@gmail.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
