<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2000 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Java Security: The Sandbox That Tried Too Hard</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-nov-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-nov-2000/</guid>
      <description>The Security Dream By November 2000, Java&amp;rsquo;s security sandbox had become the most important—and most frustrating—aspect of applet development. Sun Microsystems had made bold promises: Java applets would be safe to run from any source. The sandboxing mechanism would prevent malicious code from accessing your files, your network, or your system.&#xA;The idea was revolutionary. For the first time, you could download and run code from unknown sources with reasonable confidence that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t destroy your computer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Applet Optimization: When Performance Matters</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-aug-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-aug-2000/</guid>
      <description>The Performance Problem By August 2000, the initial enthusiasm for Java applets had collided with reality. Users were experiencing slow startup times. Applets would download, then take forever to initialize. The promise of &amp;ldquo;instant interactive applications&amp;rdquo; was turning into &amp;ldquo;stare at your screen and wait.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;As a student juggling multiple projects in dorm rooms with limited resources, performance became critical. Our dormitory network had limited bandwidth. Our machines had limited RAM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Applets In Dorms: The Browser Wars Begin</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-feb-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/java-applets-in-dorms-feb-2000/</guid>
      <description>Java: The Future of Computing? In February 2000, just two months after the Y2K celebration, the tech world buzzed with a different promise: write once, run anywhere. Java was going to revolutionize computing. Sun Microsystems was betting big on applets—small Java programs that would run in web browsers, turning the browser into a universal application platform.&#xA;As an NTU student in the dorms, I had front-row access to this revolution. Every lab machine had Java installed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
