<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2002 on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/2002/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2002 on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/2002/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Prototypes: Wireless Devices Finally Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-aug-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bluetooth-prototypes-aug-2002/</guid>
      <description>The Bluetooth Promise By August 2002, Bluetooth had been standardized for a few years, but actual working implementations were still rare. The promise was revolutionary: wirelessly connect your phone to headsets, computers, other devices—all without wires, all at close range.&#xA;At Motorola, we saw Bluetooth as the future. Instead of wired connections or limited infrared, devices could communicate wirelessly over a distance of 10 meters. You could leave your headset at your desk and walk around the office with your phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3G Rollout: The Future of Mobile Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/3g-rollout-thrills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2002 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/3g-rollout-thrills/</guid>
      <description>Moving to Motorola In 2002, I left academia and joined Motorola Mobile Devices. The timing was perfect. Motorola was at the center of the 3G revolution—the transition from 2G networks (which enabled SMS and basic data) to 3G networks (which promised high-speed data and multimedia).&#xA;The 3G Vision The promise was intoxicating. Imagine a mobile phone that could stream video, enable real-time applications, support navigation and location services. 3G would deliver megabits per second instead of kilobits.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
