<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infrastructure on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infrastructure on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oracle AI World 2025: Enterprise AI from Promise to Production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oracle-ai-world-2025/</guid>
      <description>The AI Inflection Point At Oracle AI World 2025, a clear message emerged: AI isn&amp;rsquo;t just another technology trend—it&amp;rsquo;s the bridge between decades of enterprise data and the future of business innovation.&#xA;Unlocking Enterprise Data&amp;rsquo;s True Potential Oracle founder Larry Ellison framed the opportunity succinctly: &amp;ldquo;AI offers the highest-value technology we have ever seen so far.&amp;rdquo; The critical insight? Most AI models train on internet data, missing the real competitive advantage: enterprise databases containing mission-critical business information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Weeks in Batam: Bringing NVIDIA GB200 to Life on the Data Plane</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gb200-batam-data-plane-rollout/</guid>
      <description>Three weeks in Batam, Indonesia in March 2025. Not a vacation - something far more meaningful. I was there to help bring the NVIDIA GB200 data plane to life, working alongside some of the brightest minds at OCI and NVIDIA. This was the moment where cutting-edge technology meets real-world infrastructure, and I got to be part of making it happen.&#xA;Related readings:&#xA;Behind the Scenes: NVIDIA GB200 NVL72 on OCI APIs - Technical deep dive on the NVIDIA GB200 and OCI integration Supercluster: NVIDIA Blackwell Dedicated Alloy - OCI&amp;rsquo;s Supercluster offering with Blackwell GPUs Nvidia GB200 NVL72 Now Available via Oracle Cloud - Data Center Dynamics coverage of the launch The Mission: Time to Market When I arrived in Batam, the pressure was real.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wi-Fi Experiments: From Lab to Campus Networks (1999-2000)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-experiments-journey-1999-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wifi-experiments-journey-1999-2000/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Revolution Begins (July 1999) By July 1999, Wi-Fi technology was emerging from IEEE 802.11 specifications into practical reality. Singapore, as a forward-thinking tech hub, was one of the first places to experiment with widespread wireless networking. As an NTU student, I had access to some of these early deployments, and the possibilities seemed limitless.&#xA;I spent weeks debugging solutions for wireless connectivity. The early Wi-Fi standards had significant challenges. Signal attenuation was unpredictable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
