<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rikkisnah.github.io/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wi-Fi Scaling: From Lab Experiments to Campus Networks</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/wifi-experiments-singapore-2000/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/wifi-experiments-singapore-2000/</guid>
      <description>From Lab Success to Production By May 2000, our Wi-Fi experiments from 1999 had proven successful enough that NTU was considering a campus-wide deployment. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about adding more access points; it was about understanding how wireless networks could scale from experimental hobby to critical infrastructure.&#xA;The challenge shifted from &amp;ldquo;can we do this?&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;how do we do this reliably for hundreds of users simultaneously?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Scaling Wireless Networks I spent weeks scaling solutions, grappling with the complexities of managing a distributed network of access points.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wi-Fi Experiments Singapore: Reflections from 1999</title>
      <link>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/wifi-experiments-singapore-1999/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 1999 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rikkisnah.github.io/posts/wifi-experiments-singapore-1999/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Revolution Begins By July 1999, Wi-Fi technology was emerging from IEEE 802.11 specifications into practical reality. Singapore, as a forward-thinking tech hub, was one of the first places to experiment with widespread wireless networking. As an NTU student, I had access to some of these early deployments, and the possibilities seemed limitless.&#xA;The Technical Frontier I spent weeks debugging solutions for wireless connectivity. The early Wi-Fi standards had significant challenges.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
