<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Rik Kisnah - Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Rik Kisnah - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mauritius Summer Holidays 2025 - Three Weeks of Family, Legacy, and New Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mauritius-summer-holidays-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mauritius-summer-holidays-2025/</guid>
      <description>I spent three unforgettable weeks in Mauritius during July-August 2025. This trip was special in so many ways - it was about honoring family legacy, building new opportunities, and celebrating the people who matter most.&#xA;1. Baptism of Laxmi Villa - A Dream Reborn Estelle and I completed the renovation of Laxmi Villa, the house Dad and Ma built in 1999 after I left Mauritius. The three-floor structure has always held meaning for our family:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Too Young to Die</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-young-to-die/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/too-young-to-die/</guid>
      <description>A poem for my brother. Reflecting on life, family, and the passage of time. In Remembrance Memorial and Remembrance for Ranjiv&#xA;Too Young to Die Once I was four years old, i told my mama &amp;ldquo;Pretty woman walking down the streah haha&amp;rdquo; Then she shouted at me and i said mama &amp;ldquo;You ugly woman, yacking down the stream yah&amp;rdquo;&#xA;That was then and the world was smaller And everything was so simpler and life was gentler My brother and I were running down the roads in Sodnac Drinking our dad&amp;rsquo;s secret stash of cognac</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
